dominicpalmer.org github.com/dominicpalmer dominicpalmer @outlook.com

Dominic Palmer

Mobile Location Age

On Request Brighton, UK 27

Summary

An Imperial College Applied Mathematics MSc alumni and passionate software engineer, with 3 years industry experience spanning full SDLC software development, data science, statistical programming and machine learning for research and development. An advocate of clean code, clean architecture and best practices.

LANGUAGES AND LIBRARIES

Proficient C#, .NET Core/6, SQL Server, REST APIs, Dapper, DbUp, Swagger, MSTest

C++, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, STL, GoogleTest, xUnit Familiar GNU Make, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, scikit-learn, LATEX Other

Workflows

Tools Linux, Windows, Git, VSCode, Vim, Tmux, Bash/Zsh (happy at the command line), Visual Studio

Services GitHub, GitLab, Azure DevOps, Jira, Confluence, Rally, Slack, Teams

Practices Agile, Scrum, CI, CD, unit/integration testing, international teamwork (UK \leftrightarrow USA)

Experience

Belfast, NI (Remote) **Applied Systems**

Nov. 2020 - Present Software Engineer

- o Realtime Calculation Service (RCS): Full SDLC design and development of a set of microservices that calculate insurance premiums in real time according to pricing models specified by insurers. (C#, .NET 6, SQL Server)
- o Web portal: Built an internal web portal that provides management functionality for insurance document templates. (C#, ASP.NET Core, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap)
- o Applied Relay: Regular contributions made towards Applied Ireland's flagship insurance management software, plus satellite web and desktop applications. (C#, .NET, ASP.NET, WinForms)

First Central Haywards Heath, UK Jan. 2019 - Oct. 2020

Statistical Analyst/Data Scientist

- o Pricing optimisation: Built dimensionality reduction and clustering notebooks using principal component analysis, plus classification and renewal propensity models using a range of machine learning techniques. Identified a £2m underestimation of incurred loss. (Python, Pandas, NumPy, scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Seaborn)
- o ML framework: Developed a template driven, GBM-based model optimisation framework using a platform called WTW Radar, which vastly improved model iteration time frames.
- Web scrapers: Built web scrapers that parsed and merged quote XMLs. (Python, json, BeautifulSoup)

Pre-2019 Brighton, UK

Statistical Analyst at InterAnalysis; Bartender at Mitchells & Butlers

Jul. 2016 - Apr. 2018

EDUCATION

Imperial College London

London, UK

MSc in Applied Mathematics; Distinction (76%)

Oct. 2016 - Oct. 2018

← Research project: developed a genetic algorithm in C++ that simulates tumour growth in two and three-dimensional space, based on a mathematical model of evolutionary ecology (88%).

University of Sussex

Brighton, UK

BSc in Mathematics; First Class Honours (89%)

Sep. 2013 – May 2016

← Key topics: linear algebra, calculus, set theory, combinatorics, cryptography, probability, statistics.

HarvardX: Harvard's Online Course Facility

Online

CS50 Introduction to Computer Science; Distinction (93%)

Sep. 2017 - Jul. 2018

 \hookrightarrow A 12 week course on data structures and algorithms in C, plus web development using Python, JavaScript, HTML and CSS. Built CLI based 'Mastermind' games in C++, Python and SQLite3 as a final project.

Cardinal Newman Sixth Form College

Brighton, UK

A Levels; Mathematics (A^*) , Physics (A), Chemistry (B), Extended Project (A)

2011 - 2013